# 哈喽 大家好
Hello everyone
# 前段时间我们粉丝买了
Earlier, some fans bought our crayfish seasoning packs
# 我们自己做的这个小龙虾（调料）回家他不会用
But they don't know how to use it at home
# 今天我们就用这个来现场烧一个来试验一下
Today, we'll cook with it as a live demonstration
# 这里面有三包
There are three packs in it
# 这个龙虾在那个养殖场买的
We bought the crayfish from a farm
# 特别干净
These are really clean
# 特别干净的一个小龙虾
Really clean crayfish
# 然后就用一包来烧
We'll cook with a pack
# 我把虾线去了都
I'm removing the vein
# 看
Look
# 这是根啥子嘛
What's this?
# 这根就是它(龙虾）这个肠子
It's the intestine of the crayfish
# 你看嘛 这
Yeah
# 我来抽哈看抽得来不
Let me try if I can pull it out
# 小心它要咬到你哦
Careful, it bites you
# 它咬得到我呀
No way, it can't
# 我都学会了
I've learnt it
# 今天我们来试验一下3斤龙虾到底有多少个
Today, let's count how many there are in 3 jin of crayfish (1.5kg)
# 等一下我们弄完了就数一下
We'll count after we're done
# 两边给它扯住给它拨一下
Hold the two ends and pull
# 扭一下 抓到扭一下
Twist it lightly
# 就把它整出来了
Then it's out
# 最后一个
Last one
# 这个还比较顽固
which is a stubborn one
# 最后一个出来了
Last one done
# 我数一哈看有好多个
Let me count how many are there
# 我去拿筷子来
I'll get the chopsticks
# 害怕它夹到手
Or they pinch my hands
# 哪干哦
How could it be?
# 夹到它痛得很 四伯爷
It really hurts, uncle
# 2个3个4个
2, 3, 4
# 17 18 19 20
17, 18, 19, 20
# 52 54 56
52, 54, 56
# 三斤
3 jin... (1.5kg)
# 一斤20个都没得哦
Not even 20 per jin
# 我们这个虾算中等吧
So these crayfish are medium-sized
# 就是三斤的话只有56个
Only 56 crayfish for 3 jin
# 56个
# 56 个也就是说一斤的话
56... That means the count per jin is...
# 我们这个虾稍微大点的话连20个都没有
Below 20, if the crayfish are not too small
# 我们切一点这个姜跟蒜
Let's chop some ginger and garlic
# 随便什么菜 随便你好那种（厉害）的菜
Whatever dish, whatever you are good at
# 百分之八十的菜都有这个姜蒜
80% of them use ginger and garlic
# 是
True
# 这个姜的话 我们就是切大块一点可以
We just need to roughly chop the ginger
# 然后这个蒜的话宰成两三坨
Chop the garlic into a few pieces
# 切小粒就行
Just some small pieces
# 然后再切一点小米辣
And dice some "Xiaomila" chili peppers
# 增加一点点鲜辣的味道
for the savory and spicy taste
# 其实也可以加那个二荆条
Actually, "Erjingtiao" (chili) is also fine
# 如果吃不了太辣的话
if you can't handle the spiciness
# 然后配料的话我们就配点魔芋
For the sides, we just need some konjac
# 魔芋烧在龙虾里面也好吃
Konjac braised with crayfish is delicious
# 这样子整起好好看哦噶
You made it so pretty huh?
# 是不
Is it?
# 跟它波浪似的样
Looks like waves
# 我们这个青瓜加进去要最后加比较脆
The cucumbers should be added last, to keep the crunchiness
# 直接切成小条
Cut it into small strips
# 是脆的这个放进去
It will be crunchy in the dish
# 要慢慢品尝才品尝得出来这个滋味
Gotta taste it slowly to know the flavor
# 最后我们再切点小葱
Finally, let's chop some scallions
# 小葱切进去
Chop some scallions
# 最后起锅的时候再加
And add it at last, before serving
# 因为有这个底料非常的方便简单
The seasoning pack makes it very simple and convenient
# 加上自己喜欢的辅料
Just add your favorite ingredients
# 然后切点大蒜 生姜 辣椒
Chop some garlic, ginger and chili peppers
# 再加一包这个料
And add a pack of the seasoning
# 把这个料开一哈都
Need to open the pack
# 全部把它倒出来
Pour everything out
# 我们这个料不单单可以烧这个龙虾
The seasoning pack is not only good for crayfish
# 还可以烧干锅
but also for dry pots
# 因为这里面我配了孜然粉
It's because I added cumin powder in it
# 就是有香辣的那个配方在里面
I mean, there's the "Xiangla" spicy mix in it
# 好可以了
Alright, good
# 你闻哈看有一股干锅的（味道）
It smells like a dry pot, right?
# 因为放了那个孜然在里头的
That's because of the cumin
# 有点干锅的味道
So it smells like a dry pot
# 好 开始炒
Alright, let's start cooking
# 炒起炒起
Let's get started
# 来 四伯爷你的筷子
Chopsticks for you, uncle
# 我吃点黄瓜看
Let me try some cucumber
# 有味道
(Properly) flavored
# 吃是好吃 好多东西我咬不动了
It's tasty, but there are too many things I can't chew
# 没得办法得
No way
# 吃个小龙虾
I'll have a crayfish
# 用手撕来吃
Tearing it with my hands
# 没得好多点黄的了这哈的龙虾
There's not much "yellow stuff" in the crayfish
# 没得好多肉的
Not much meat either
# 啊
Um
# 我们这个料只放了一包做三斤小龙虾的话
We used only one pack of seasoning for 3 jin of crayfish
# 刚好合适噻
Just about right?
# 就是稍微淡一点点
It's a bit milder though
# 如果你们要吃重口味的话
So if you prefer a stronger flavor
# 放一包半
Use 1.5 packs
# 我说的淡是辣味的淡
By "mild" I mean mild in the spiciness
# 诶 这个还可以
Eh, this one is good
# 嗯
Um
# 一包料烧40个就味道刚刚好
One pack for 40 crayfish should be just about right
# 就是重口味的刚刚好
I mean, just about right for a strong flavor
# 好吃 就是没得什么肉现在的龙虾
It's tasty! But too little meat in the crayfish
# 吃起就停不下来
I just can't stop eating